<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wirtbot.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Update 7</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-7/</guid><description>WirtBot v3.1 A small update is being released as I am writing this.
Version 3.1 tries to remove some clutter on the Dashboard.
From now on all advanced device options are hidden behind a More button. The QR code for mobile devices is now also a button click away instead of always being displayed.
A small new feature was introduced as well. You can now add a Port to the device configuration settings.</description></item><item><title>Update 6</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-6/</guid><description>WirtBot v3 Hello,
long time no update. Over the past couple of months more people started to use WirtBot and gave Feedback.
This has lead to bugs being squashed and a more stable system overall, including new tests for the fixes.
But that alone would not be justifying an update post.
So here is the real update:
AdBlocking has been removed from WirtBot.
The dependencies that made this possible were not mature enough and would need a lot of work to fit the WirtBot use-case.</description></item><item><title>Update 5</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-5/</guid><description>Update 5: Time to maintain A year is over, a project complete.
As of today, the international womens day 2021, the WirtBot project is going into maintenance mode.
All planned features have been integrated and the testing harness covers them.
If you have never heard of the project you can check out the repository or homepage.
What changed since the last update? The last update was the preparation to get to this final stage.</description></item><item><title>Update 4</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-4/</guid><description>Update 4: V2 of the WirtBot lost some weight After using the WirtBot for a while I noticed the cruft I loaded onto myself.
Maintaining the WirtBot + ansible scripts etc. while already having it containerized and the audience, despite my attempts to make it simple to use, being highly technical nonetheless just made no sense.
If you use this tech you probably already have a pretty good grasp of Linux and networks.</description></item><item><title>Update 3</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/update-3/</guid><description>Update 3 Already the third update and some things have changed on the surface, more on that at the end of the page.
But underneath the hood, that is where things were really changed. So lets dive right in.
Single Docker container First of all, the functionality that ensures the systems functionality is now encapsulated inside a single Docker container. The only exception is CoreDNS. It still resides in its own container and only the Corefile is shared via Docker volumes over the local filesystem.</description></item><item><title>22.11.20</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/22.11.20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/22.11.20/</guid><description>22.11.20 WirtBot version 1.5 With version 1.5 many things changed on the Interface codebase and the System-Tests.
Instead of relying on nightwatch, the System-Tests are now written in NodeJS - leveraging the amazing playwright to interact with browsers.
The reason for the nightwatch to playwright change were tests of input validity. While there seemed no straight forward way to achieve it in nightwatch, it became page.$eval(element-selector, e =&amp;gt; e.validity.valid) with playwright.</description></item><item><title>8.11.20</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/8.11.20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/8.11.20/</guid><description>8.11.20 The wirt-installer is now wirtbot-installer on your computer and will look for the wirtbot-installer.config.json file to load previously input settings.
If you come from a version before 1.4.4 please rename you old wirt-installer.config.json to wirtbot-installer.config.json before updating your server to avoid repeating all your info.</description></item><item><title>31.10.20</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/31.10.20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/31.10.20/</guid><description>31-10-20 Happy Halloween!
The WirtBot build-system has been updated and the whole system, including WireGuard, are running in a single Docker container.
To achieve this the container needs to be run with NET_ADMIN capabilities.
The Readme and setup documentation has been updated.
If you are already running a WirtBot VPS and want to update do the following:
Save your dasboard backup from http://wirtbot.wirt.internal
Rebuild a clean VPS with Debian 10</description></item><item><title>21.10.20</title><link>https://wirtbot.com/blog/21.10.20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://wirtbot.com/blog/21.10.20/</guid><description>21.10.20 If you already installed the server please update your installer to at least version 1.0.8 and run the update function.
The firewall was not configured correctly by ansible before that version. A simple typo disable it in the ansible script.</description></item></channel></rss>